Guide to the Robert Dash Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Robert Dash papers
1954-2010
GEN MSS 792
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
18.51
(34 boxes) + 2 broadside and 1 art.
The papers include correspondence, writings, journals, sketchbooks, workbooks, photographs, clippings and other papers, artwork, and audiovisual materials. Correspondence includes letters with many fellow poets, painters, and gardeners. Writings include typescripts and manuscripts by Dash and others. Journals and workbooks include writings, drawings, and other documents pertaining mainly to paintings and the evolution of the gardens at Dash's Long Island estate, Madoo. Artwork includes drawings, oil paintings, lithographs, and photographs by Dash, James Schuyler, and Joe Brainard.
Dash, Robert
Brainard, Joe, 1942-1994
Schuyler, James
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Granary Books, Inc., on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund and the Alfred Z. Baker, Jr. Fund, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 35 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 36 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 37 (microscope slides) Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Robert Dash
Robert Dash (1931- ) is an American painter, writer, and gardener. Dash's Long Island estate and garden, Madoo, is incorporated as the nonprofit Madoo Conservancy.
Scope and Contents
The papers include correspondence, writings, journals, sketchbooks, workbooks, photographs, clippings and other papers, artwork, and audiovisual materials. Correspondence includes letters with many fellow poets, painters, and gardeners. Writings include typescripts and manuscripts by Dash and others. Journals and workbooks include writings, drawings, and other documents pertaining mainly to paintings and the evolution of the gardens at Dash's Long Island estate, Madoo. Artwork includes drawings, oil paintings, lithographs, and photographs by Dash, James Schuyler, and Joe Brainard.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series: I. Correspondence, circa 1950s-2000s. II. Writings, circa 1970s-2000s. III. Journals, 1954-2010. IV. Sketchbooks and workbooks, 1967-2004. V. Photographs, circa 1954-2004. VI. Clippings and other papers, circa 1960s-2008. VII. Artwork, 1960-1964, undated. VII. Audiovisual materials, 1996-1998.
Gardening -- United States; Painters -- United States -- Archives; Poets, American -- Archives; Madoo Conservancy (Sagaponack, N.Y.); Audiocassettes; Born digital; Drawings (visual works); Lithographs; Oil paintings (visual works); Photographs; Sound recordings; Videocassettes; Painters -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Brainard, Joe, 1942-1994; Dash, Robert; Schuyler, James; Madoo Conservancy
- Correspondence, circa 1950s-2000s; Series I; 2.5; (2 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Oranized into two subseries: garden and personal correspondence and literary and art correspondence. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  - Garden and personal correspondence
    - Miscellaneous A (Box 1)
    - AAAHH (Box 1)
    - Alex (?) (Box 1)
    - American Embassy (Box 1)
    - Amies, Hardy (Box 1)
    - Ashton (?) (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous B (Box 1)
    - Balliett, Nancy & Whitney (Box 1)
    - Becker, Jonathan (Box 1)
    - Bender, Pat (Box 1)
    - Bhiram, Nayana (Box 1)
    - Birch, Pat (Box 1)
    - Britton, Donald (Box 1)
    - Bugsma, Judy (Box 1)
    - Burr, David Shepard (Box 1)
    - Burroughs, Diana (Box 1)
    - Bush, George H. W. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous C (Box 1)
    - Campbell, Larry (Box 1)
    - Celender, Don (Box 1)
    - Chase, Lyn (Box 1)
    - Chesshire, Charles (Box 1)
    - Committee for Nonviolent Action (Box 1)
    - Cook, Peter (Box 1)
    - Country Art Gallery (Box 1)
    - Cox, Madison (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous D (Box 1)
    - Dale, Mary (Box 1)
    - Darke, Rick (Box 1)
    - Davis, Peter (Box 1)
    - Dingwall-Nain (?), Catherine (Box 1)
    - Dorra, Mary T. (Box 1)
    - Downtown/Uptown Gallery Lok (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous E (Box 1)
    - Echlin, Letitia (?) (Box 1)
    - Eickengreen, Laurie (Box 1)
    - Elaine Benson Gallery (Box 1)
    - Elliott, Inger (Box 1)
    - Elsley, Billie and (?) (Box 1)
    - Eltz, Peter (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes two letters from Dash.
    - Miscellaneous F (Box 1)
    - Feld, Stuart P. (Box 1)
    - Feldman, Lester (Box 1)
    - Fields, Laura Kemper (Box 1)
    - Fields, Michael (Box 1)
    - Fleming, William J. (Box 1)
    - Fox, Connie (Box 1)
    - Franklin, Michael (Box 1)
    - Frederick, Bill (Box 1)
    - Frederick, Dolly (Box 1)
    - French, Kate (Box 1)
    - Friedel, Helmut (Box 1)
    - du Fresne, Christine (Box 1)
    - Fugger, Rose-Marie, Countess (Box 1)
    - Fundação Botânica Margaret Mee (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous G (Box 1)
    - Gallery North (Box 1)
    - Garden Book Club, 2 (Box 1)
    - Gardening related (Box 1)
    - Garrett, Fergus (Box 1)
    - Goodwin, Nancy (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous H (Box 1)
    - M.L.H. (Box 1)
    - Hales, Mick and Christine (Box 1)
    - Hales, Mick and Katherine (Box 1)
    - Hall, Lee (RISD) (Box 1)
    - Hampton, Mark (Box 1)
    - Hanson, Wendy (Box 1)
    - Hatshepsut (Box 1)
    - Hayward, Gordon (Box 1)
    - Heckscher Museum (Box 1)
    - Henne, Dagmar (Box 1)
    - Heyman, Ken (Box 1)
    - Hobhouse, Penelope (Box 1)
    - Howard, Jane (Box 1)
    - Hughes, Jeff (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous I (Box 1)
    - Idone, Christopher J. (Box 1)
    - Ingram, C. (Box 1)
    - Irvine, Keith (Box 1)
    - Irvine, Chippy & Keith (Box 1)
    - Permanent Mission of Italy to the U.N. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous J (Box 1)
    - Jeffery, Richard (Box 1)
    - Johnson, Lawrence J. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous K (Box 1)
    - Michiko (Box 1)
    - Kemper, James & Millie (Box 1)
    - Kirkwood, James (Box 1)
    - Kulicke, Adair (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous L (Box 1)
    - Lane, John and Jane (Box 1)
    - Lennard, Erica (Box 1)
    - Leveque, Patricia (Box 1)
    - Linda (?) (Box 1)
    - Lissandrello, George (Box 1)
    - Logan, Margaret (Box 1)
    - Long, Robert (Box 1)
    - Lord, Pamela (Box 1)
    - Lowe, Fred (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous M (Box 1)
    - Marta, Karen & Justen (Box 1)
    - McEvoy, Marian (Box 1)
    - de Mertenil, Cécile (Box 1)
    - Miller, Ann (Box 1)
    - Miller, Lisa (Box 1)
    - Moonan, Wendy Lyon (Box 1)
    - Morgan, Margaret (Box 1)
    - Morgan, Robert (Box 1)
    - Morris, Emma (Box 1)
    - Mortimer, Sengha & Peter (Box 1)
    - Munroe, Enid (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous N (Box 1)
    - Nassau County Fine Arts Museum (Box 1)
    - Nelson, Holly (Box 1)
    - Nelson-Atkins Museum of Art (Box 1)
    - New York Botanical Garden (Box 1)
    - New York State Council on the Arts (Box 1)
    - New York Studio School of Drawing, Painting, and Sculpture (Box 1)
    - New York University (Box 1)
    - Newark Museum (Box 1)
    - Nissen, Jane (Hamish Hamilton Childrens' Books) (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous O (Box 1)
    - Oetker, August & Alexandra (Box 1)
    - Oetker, Georgia (Box 1)
    - Osborne, Vals & José Moreno-Lacalle (Box 1)
    - Otto, Don (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous P (Box 1)
    - Parsons, Randall (Box 1)
    - The P.E.N. (David Carver) (Box 1)
    - Penny McCall Foundation (Box 1)
    - Pitney Farm (Box 1)
    - Portnow, Marjorie (Box 1)
    - Princeton University Press (Jan Lilly) (Box 1)
    - Public Art Fund Inc. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous R (Box 1)
    - Raffan, Keith (Box 1)
    - Rambusch, Catha Grace (Box 1)
    - Random House (Box 1)
    - Raver, Tina (Box 1)
    - Rees, Sue (Box 1)
    - Register, John (Box 1)
    - Reif, Rita (Box 1)
    - Roach, Margaret (Box 1)
    - Robinson, John Seeman (Menil Collection) (Box 1)
    - Rockefeller, David (Box 1)
    - Rohatyn, Elizabeth (Box 1)
    - Rohatyn, Pierre (Box 1)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 1)
    - Rothchild, Susan Berns (Box 1)
    - Royal Horticultural Society (Box 1)
    - Royce, Doris (Box 1)
    - Russ, Linda (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous S (Box 1)
    - Seaver (?) (Box 1)
    - Seebohm, Caroline (Box 1)
    - Slaugher, Jane (Box 1)
    - Soriano, Alex (Box 1)
    - Soriano, Jose M. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous T (Box 1)
    - Tappan, Julia (Box 1)
    - Taylor, Gordon (Box 1)
    - Tower Hill Botanic Garden (Box 1)
    - Tupitsya, Victor (Box 1)
    - Upton Lodge Galleries (Box 1)
    - Vered Art Gallery (Box 1)
    - Verey, Rosemary (Box 1)
    - Vicente, Harriet (Box 1)
    - Vreeland, Alexander & Sandra (Box 1)
    - Wamsler, Karl & Honoré (Box 1)
    - Wave Hill (Box 1)
    - Weatherlys, Sarah & Virginia (Box 1)
    - Weinberg, Jill (Lennon-Weinberg, Inc.) (Box 1)
    - Weller, Mrs. Frank H. (Box 1)
    - Wenner, Frances (Box 1)
    - Wheeler, David & Simon Dorrell (Box 1)
    - White, Claire (Box 1)
    - Whiteside, Katherine (Box 1)
    - Whitman, Alden (Box 1)
    - Wilson, Jane (Box 1)
    - Wilkinson, Shannon M. (Box 1)
    - Williamson, Barbara (Box 1)
    - Woepe, Hilda (Box 1)
    - Worcester Art Museum (Box 1)
    - Zabar, Judith M. (Box 1)
    - Zabriskie Gallery (Box 1)
    - Zohn, Ngaere Macray (Sagapress) (Box 1)
  - Literary and art correspondence
    - Alderson, Brooke (Box 2)
    - Andre, Michael (Box 2)
    - Ashbery, John, 2 (Box 2)
    - Berkson, Lynn O'Hare (Box 2)
    - Chase, Richard Hartley (Box 2)
    - Cooper, Dennis (Box 2)
    - Corbett, Bill (Box 2)
    - Crase, Doug, 3 (Box 2)
    - Crile, Susan (Box 2)
    - Dash, Robert, 3 (Box 2)
      Correspondence by Dash includes letters to his parents, Mr. and Mrs. Emanuel Dash, other artists, etc.
    - Dash, Mr. or Mrs. Emanuel (Box 2)
    - Downes, Rackstraw (Box 2)
    - Elmslie, Kenward (Box 2)
    - Epstein, Jason (Box 2)
    - Fagin, Larry (Box 2)
    - Finlay, Ian Hamilton, 2 (Box 2)
    - Fischbach, Marilyn (Box 2)
    - Forrest Myers, Frosty, Debbie, and Rio (Box 2)
    - Fourcade, Xavier (Box 2)
    - Giorno, John (Box 2)
    - Golde, Morris (Box 2)
    - Guest, Barbara, 2 (Box 2)
    - Guest, Hadley (Box 2)
    - Guggenheim Museum (Box 2)
    - Hartigan, Grace (Box 2)
    - Hempel, Amy (Box 2)
    - Henry, Gerrit (Box 2)
    - Howell, Anthony (Box 2)
    - Kabakov, Kya and Emilia (Box 2)
    - Katz, Alex (Box 2)
    - Kermani, David Khodamorad (Box 2)
    - Kernan, Nathan (Box 2)
    - Koethe, John and Susan (Box 2)
    - Koethe, Susan (Box 2)
    - de Kooning, Elaine (Box 2)
    - Koethe, John, 2 (Box 2)
    - Krasner, Lee (Box 2)
    - Kulicke, Barbara (Box 2)
    - Leigh, Ted (Box 2)
    - Lesueur, Joe (Box 2)
    - Lichtenstein, Roy (Box 2)
    - Lubin, Ernest (Box 2)
    - Magriel, Paul (Box 2)
    - Marta, Karen (Parkett) (Box 2)
    - McCall, Anthony and Cary (Box 2)
    - McCoy, Jason (Box 2)
    - Morris Gallery (Box 2)
    - Nicholson, Roy (Box 2)
    - North, Charles (Box 2)
    - Padgett, Ron (Box 2)
    - Park, Darragh A., 2 (Box 2)
    - Parrish Art Museum (Box 2)
    - Pisano, Ronald G. (Box 2)
    - Polach, Frank, 3 (Box 2)
    - Porter, Anne, 3 (Box 2)
    - Porter, Fairfield (Box 2)
    - Purdum, Becky, 2 (Box 2)
    - Rorem, Ned (Box 2)
    - Schjeldahl, Peter, 2 (Box 2)
    - Schuyler, James, 5 (Box 2)
    - Schafner, Perdita, 2 (Box 2)
    - Storr, Robert, 3 (Box 2)
    - Tilton, Jack (Box 2)
    - Vonnegut, Kurt (Box 2)
    - Waldman, Diane and Paul (Box 2)
    - Winkfield, Trevor, 3 (Box 2)
    - Youngerman, Jack (Box 2)
- Writings, circa 1970s-2000s; Series II; 3; (4 boxes)
  Organized into two subseries: Writings by Robert Dash and writings by others.
  - Writings by Robert Dash
    - William the Caterpillar (Box 3)
    - Several Dash Manuscripts, 2 (Box 3)
    - "Crazy Alice" (Box 3)
    - "Probably there can never be..." (Box 3)
    - The Second Soup Bowl (Box 3)
    - Ingredients of a Room (Box 3)
    - The Man with the Golden Brain (Box 3)
    - Assorted notes (Box 3)
    - The American Man's Garden (Box 3)
    - Albert Pinkham Ryder (Box 3)
    - Review of Innisfree: An American Garden (Box 3)
    - Misc notes on small paper (Box 3)
    - Assorted writings, 2 (Box 3)
    - Catalog - Artists of Suffolk County, Part VI, Contemporary Prints (Box 3)
    - Catalog - Flowers (Box 3)
    - Catalog - Light of the South Fork (Box 3)
    - Catalog - Robert Dash: Florilegium (Box 3)
    - Catalog - Robert Dash: Recent Paintings (Box 3)
    - Catlog - Robert Dash: Selected Works, 1961-2002 (Box 3)
    - "Do You See the Bird..." (Box 3)
    - Exhibition Announcements (Box 3)
    - A Master of Shadow and Light (Box 3)
    - "I Think I Would Like to Begin this Talk..." (Box 3)
    - June 8, 1960 (Box 3)
    - Loose page accompanying a manuscript (Box 3)
    - The Death of a Field (Box 3)
    - A Man in Blue (Box 3)
    - The Poetry Pot (Box 3)
    - Untitled play (Box 3)
    - Villa des Amis (Box 3)
  - Writings by others
    - Ashbery, John. "Happy Autumn Fields" (Box 3)
    - Ashbery, John. "The Serious Doll" (Box 3)
    - Crase, Doug. "The Care of Plants," and "The Winter House" (Box 3)
    - Crase, Doug. "The House of Sagg" (Box 3)
    - Guest, Barbara. "Lights of my Eyes" (Box 3)
    - Henry, Gerrit, "Already" (Box 3)
    - Koethe, John. "The Near Future" (Box 3)
    - Poem Painting flyer (Box 3)
    - Schjeldahl, Peter. "October Classic" (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James. "An East Window on Elizabeth Street" (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James."For Bob on his Birthday" (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James. "Korean Mums" (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James."People Who See Bubbles Rise" (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James."To a Water Colorist" (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James."Voyage au Tour de mes Cartes" (Box 3)
    - Crase, Douglas. AMERIFIL.EXT (Box 3)
    - Crase, Doug. A Review of Wave by John Ashbery (Box 3)
    - Crase, Doug. "The Revisionist" (Box 3)
    - Crase, Douglas and Robert Dash (Box 3)
    - CTC - "To RWD - Windows on a pond..." (Box 3)
    - Elslie, Kenward. "The Warm Winter" (Box 3)
    - Hanran, E. - Winnie Is (Box 3)
    - Henry, Gerrit. "The Magic of Leaving" (Box 3)
    - Henry, Gerrit. "An Occasional Sonnet" (Box 3)
    - Henry, Gerrit. "Put to the Test" (Box 3)
    - Howell(?), Anthony. "Natural History" (Box 3)
    - Howell, Anthony and Robert Dash - Exquisite Corpse (Box 3)
    - Koethe, John. Dorothy Wordsworth: Poems (Box 3)
    - Koethe, John. The Little Boy (Box 3)
    - Koethe, John. The Near Future (Box 3)
    - Koethe, John. Packet of poems (Box 3)
    - Koethe, John. The Room Next to the Mind (Box 3)
    - Mattolini, Mario. "The Locomotive" (Box 3)
    - Morley, Hilda. "Old Savage" (Box 3)
    - Schjeldahl, Peter. "The Artist" (Box 3)
    - Schjeldahl, Peter. "Beasts" (Box 3)
    - Schjeldahl, Peter. From a Honeymoon Journal (Box 3)
    - Schjeldahl, Peter. "Lobster out of Water" (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James. "Buttered Greens" (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James. The Crystal Lithium (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James and Robert Dash. "The Climax" and "White and Blue" (Box 3)
    - Spender, Stephen (Translated by Louis Aragon). "Chute d'une Cite" (Box 3)
    - Unknown - Essay starting "Thanks to Nigel Nicholson's..." (Box 3)
    - Unknown, "Poems that Begin 'Exploding like a Flock...'" (Box 3)
    - Unknown - "First Four Chapters of an Untitled Work..." (Box 3)
    - Unknown. Poem on microscope slides, 1979
      General note
      10 microscope slides in a wooden slide box.
    - Welish, Marjorie. "The Mercurial World of Paul Magrial" (Box 3)
    - Winkfield, Trevor. "A Season'd Regalia" (Box 3)
    - Winkfield, Trevor. "Depraved Bumpkins and Lesser Worries" (Box 3)
    - Winkfield, Trevor and Robert Dash. Exquisite Corpse (Box 3)
    - Berrigan, Ted. The Sonnets (Box 3)
    - Guest, Barbara. The Location of Things (Box 3)
    - Padgett, Ron. In Advance of the Broken Arm (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James, ed. 49 South (Box 3)
    - Schuyler, James and Charles North, eds. Broadway (Box 3)
    - Crase, Doug. "Replevin" (Box 4)
    - Crase, Doug. "Saggaponnack" (Box 4)
    - Howell, Anthony, "Herring were buried in nearby fields..." (Box 4)
    - Kernan, Natha. "Allée of Poplars" (Box 4)
    - Schuyler, James. "Dec. 28, 1974" (Box 4)
    - Storr, Robert. "Bob - Herewith Santa Baby" (Box 4)
    - Storr, Robert. Drawing with inscription, 1987 December 22 (Box 4)
    - Unknown. "Heron Weather" (Box 4)
    - Unknown. "Noise in the Sky" (Box 4)
    - Unknown. "Sagg Beach" (Box 4)
    - Koethe, John. "The Little Boy" (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - Koethe, John. "The Little Boy" (Box 6 (Oversize))
- Journals, 1954-2010; Series III; 2.67; (6 boxes)
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Journal, 1954 January 15 - 1955 June 26 (Box 7)
  - Commonbook, 1956? (Box 7)
  - Italy II, 1956? (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1956 April 30 - 1956 Aug 18 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1956 Oct 8 - 1959 Mar 6 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1969 December 3 - 1970 March 11 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1975 September 3 1976 October 23 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1978 May 25 - 1982 (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Journal, 1979 September 16 - 1980 September 5 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1980 September 14 - 1980 December 31 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1982 January 9 - 1983 September 26 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1983 September 28 - 1985 April 10 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1985 April 18 1986 August 6 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1987 December 25 - 1988?/1989? December 16 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1998 May 28 - 1999 August 26 (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Journal, 1989 January 26 - 1989 December 17 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1991 - 1992 May 9 (Box 7)
  - Garden book Madoo, 1993 March 20 - 1993 September 3 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1992 August 14 - 1993? November 11 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1993 November 12 - 1994 July 3 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1994 July 6 - 1995 August 27 (Box 9)
  - Journal, 1995 September 13 - 1997 June (Box 9)
  - Holland, 1996 Mar 13 - 25 (Box 7)
  - Journal, 1999 November - 2002 July 1 (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Journal, 2002 July 6 - 2004 July 7 (Box 9)
  - Journal, 2004 August 25 - 2005 January 30 (Box 9)
  - Journal, 2006 February 2 - 2008 March 22 (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Madoo order book, 2008 December - 2010 February (Box 12 (Oversize))
- Sketchbooks and workbooks, 1967-2004; Series IV; 2.25; (5 boxes)
  - Sketches and writings, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Sketches and writings, 1971-1972 (Box 13)
  - Pencil sketches, 1972 March 9, 24 (Box 13)
  - Pencil sketches, 1972 February 24 - 1972 March 9 (Box 13)
  - Sketches, 1972 March (Box 13)
  - Ink sketches, 1977 August 8 - 1977 September 23 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Ink sketches, 1977 September 25 - November 27 (Box 13)
  - Ink sketches, 1977 November 28 - 1978 January 1 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Ink sketches, 1977 December 28 - 1978 March 1 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Annie's Den workbook, 1991 February 21 - November 14 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Sketchbook, Gomez Garden, 1996?-1997 (Box 13)
  - Pencil sketches, 1995 January 9 - 1995 March 5 (Box 13)
  - Isham Garden, 1999 January 4 - 2004 January 18 (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - Workbook, 2000 May (Box 13)
  - Ink sketches and Parrish lecture, undated (Box 17 (Oversize))
- Photographs, circa 1954-2004; Series V; 4.25; (7 boxes)
  - Photographs (Box 18)
  - Photographs (Box 19)
    Includes Pianofest album, photographs of Robert Dash, and art slides
  - Madoo slides (Box 20)
  - Madoo slides (Box 21)
  - Madoo slides (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous slides (Box 23)
  - Madoo photograph album, photographs removed from frames (Box 24 (Oversize))
- Clippings and other papers, circa 1960s-2008; Series VI; 2.33; (4 boxes)
  - Scrapbook 2.1, 2 (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook 2.2, 3 (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook 2.3, 4 (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook 2.4 (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook 2.5, 3 (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook 2.6, 4 (Box 25)
  - Loose clippings, circa 2005-2008 (Box 26)
  - Clippings and other papers relating to Madoo (Box 27)
    This box also contains personal papers, including a folder of Robert Dash biographical material.
  - Artwork, "Becky and Peter were married Dec. 15, 1989 NYC" (Box 28 (Oversize))
  - Madoo posters (Box 28 (Oversize))
  - Sheet music (Box 28 (Oversize))
- Artwork, 1960-1964, undated; Series VII; 0.46; (3 boxes) + 2 broadside and 1 art
  Arranged alphabetically by artist.
  - Brainard, Joe. ["I Usually Find That There is Not Much You Can Do With A Painting But Look At It."], 1964 (Box 29 (Oversize))
    10 x 13 inch drawing on paper. Signed "Brainard-64."
  - Brainard, Joe. "Sack You / For / Being / Bob /Dash" on brown paper bag. (Box 30 (Oversize))
  - Porter, Fairfield. [Humphrey] (Box 29 (Oversize))
  - Schuyler, James. "The Yvonne Clare Story", 1960 (Box 31)
    Yvonne Clare is a series of twenty photographs attached to paper, most with annotations on the paper. Photographs were removed from frames.
  - Schuyler, James and Robert Dash. Poem / painting "Without you / oaks and elms / turned pear and apple colors / anyway".], circa 1960s (Box 32 (Art))
    Signed by both poet and painter. 48 ½ x 48 inches.
  - Schuyler, James and Robert Dash. "Garden". [color] (Box 33 (Broadside))
    Lithographs by Robert Dash, lines by James Schuyler. Lithography Venture, 1971. Edition of 130 copies with 65 copies in color and 65 copies in black and white. Printed by Yann Samson with Jean-Pierre Remind at Shorewood Atelier. Each lithograph signed by painter and poet. 31 12/ x 43 inches.
  - Schuyler, James and Robert Dash. "Garden". [black and white] (Box 34 (Broadside))
- Audiovisual materials, 1996-1998; Series VIII; 0.42; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Audiocassettes, Winter in the Garden, 1996, 1998 (Box 35)
  - CDs, Winter in the Garden (Box 35)
  - Dash duelling trowels, 1996 June; GENMSS792_0001; 1; 01:04:17 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002093672914)
  - Dash: Duelling trowels, 1996 June; GENMSS792_0002; 1; 01:04:44 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002093672922)
    Filmed by Anthony McCall.
  - OVID eo, Artata Lanamax, 20 minutes, GENMSS792_0003; 1; 00:20:04 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002093672930)
- Restricted fragile, 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Computer media
    - [no label information], 2011-genm-41567-0001; 1; Media is cracked and unreadable. (Box 36)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - 5/4/04 Madoo Posters, 2011-genm-41567-0002; 1 (Box 36)
    - System 7.6 1C1 #2, 2011-genm-41567-0003; 1 (Box 36)
  - Unknown. Poem on microscope slides., 1979 (Box 37)